## **DINA RUBAKHA**

d.rubakha@hotmail.com 847.660.4897 8840 N. Lacrosse Ave. # 1A Skokie, Illinois 60077 USA

NATIVE ENGLISH SPEAKER

CITIZENSIP: USA D.O.B: January 17, 1976 GENDER: Female

MARITAL STATUS: Single

**PROFILE** 



TEFL certified instructor with a bachelor's degree in Education and English Literature. Experience teaching, tutoring and classroom assisting in Secondary Educational settings. Generated lesson plans, accommodation lessons for ELL, English Language Learners, modified plans for small group sessions and tutored in school and volunteer programs.

### **EDUCATION**

**B.A. IN ENGLISH B.S. IN EDUCATION** TEACHER CERTIFICATION

Loyola University, Chicago, IL USA

• 5 months on site practicum student teacher

120-HOUR TEFL CERTIFICATION

TEFL Institute, Chicago, IL USA

• 100 hours of training with 20 hours of diverse classroom observation

ELL (ENGLISH LANGUAGE LEARNER) CERTIFICATION

National-Louis University (Illinois Resource Center), Arlington Heights, IL USA

2009

2011

2007

## RELATED WORK EXPERIENCE

ELL (ENGLISH LANGUAGE LEARNER) CLASSROOM ASSISTANT Niles North High School, Skokie, IL USA

2008-2009

- Worked with individual students and/ or pairs to develop reading proficiency: modeled reading strategies, fostered critical thinking, and helped attain success in comprehension
- Supplemented ELL class content for students: read text, and created documents
- Assisted students with additional assignments and provided needed supports

# ELL (ENGLISH LANGUAGE LEARNER) TEACHER

Niles West High School, Skokie, IL USA

- Created a curriculum for summer school public speaking course
- Constructed lesson plans, amended lessons when necessary
- Instructed students and assisted them in preparation for speeches

2008

## ELL (ENGLISH LANGUAGE LEARNER) TUTOR

2007-2008

Niles North High School, Skokie, IL USA

- Worked with students to format essays, corrected phrasing, grammar, and analyze literature; concentrated on generating ideas, writing outlines and summaries
- Assisted students with math lessons: geometry and algebra
- Created a district Newsletter
- Copied documents for classes and answered phones

#### ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

#### ADMINISTRATIVE ASSISTANT

2009-2011

Maritime Brokers & Consultants, Deerfield, IL USA

- Coordinated Office move: document allocation, furniture relocation, notifications
- Provided administrative support to the office manager; assisted with individual projects (analyzing data, negotiating prices, basic research)
- Retrieved, organized and distributed information to staff and clients
- Handled company land & mobile lines
- Monitored and completed supply orders; purchased corporate gifts and accessories
- Responsible for domestic and international travel arrangements and gift orders
- Generated memos, emails, letters, FedEx and standard mailings

#### OFFICE CLERK / DATA ENTRY

2004-2007

Healthstar Associates, Lincolnwood, IL USA

- Entered invoice data into Representatives Profit Management Systems database
- Coded, copied, and distributed copies of invoices to representatives
- Resolved errors with appropriate manufacturers in regard to checks and invoice discrepancies
- Generated monthly manufacturer year to date sales reports, and monthly commission reports
- Created and maintained Excel spreadsheets

#### **CASHIER**

Jewel Food Stores, Skokie, IL USA

2002-2008

Amazing Savings Store, Morton Grove, IL USA

1999-2004

- Administered sales-cash transaction, coordinated breaks among cashiers
- Instructed customers on use of self-check system
- Provided customer service and handled phone calls

## QUALIFICATIONS

#### Volunteer

Youth Organization Umbrella (Y.O.U.)-Youth Service organization

2011

Volunteer

Community Animal Rescue Effort (C.A.R.E.) -Evanston Animal Shelter

2002-2011

Conversational Spanish and Russian

Technical Proficiencies: Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook

Certificate of Academic Excellence Excellent Customer Service Award